NICK ASCHENBACH

nick.aschenbach@gmail.com 503.915.1358 San Diego, CA

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced software leader with a track record in healthcare, fintech and startup companies. I specialize in bringing new projects to life. My passion is to do what it takes to get the software out the door leading activities like supporting engineering, working closely with business teams to evolve product requirements, project management, UX design, QA, coaching and mentorship.

TECH SKILLS

Nodejs AWS Prisma Sequelize Express React / Nextjs

TDD Data science REST / GraphQL APIs

Jest Figma

Illustrator / Photoshop

EXPERIENCE

Team Lead / Head of Engineering VECKTA Corp - San Diego, CA

2020 - 2024

- Collaborated with internal and external stakeholders to build features that solve the right problems
- Developed software roadmap, planned epics, designed user experiences and broke work down into feature stories
- Reviewed code, performed quality assurance and maintained a high level of software quality
- Developed and maintained cloud and application deployment infrastructure
- Researched and evaluated new technology, 3rd party data sources and other innovations which could improve application performance
- Developed and monitored key performance indicators to ensure and communicate team success
- Built ChatGPT enabled electrical outage detector bot prototype
- Tech stack: React, Next, Vercel, Nodejs, Prisma, Postgres, AWS: RDS, S3, EC2, Cognito

- Lead development of a health care medical payments mobile application
- Developed and led agile rituals including scrum, sprint planning, demo and grooming
- Engineered RESTful APIs using Node.js on the back-end (express, sequelize, Cognito/JWT-based auth, jest)
- Developed insights for bills employing medical expert knowledge and data science techniques
- Developed React-Native front-end app to support iOS and Android devices
- Constructed Extract-Transform-Load (ETL) pipelines using AWS technologies: S3, Lambda, SQS, ECS and RDS (Postgres/MySQL)
- Employed AWS technologies: EC2, IAM, load balancers, Route53, ACM and CloudWatch Logs/Events

Software Development Engineer Hewlett-Packard - Vancouver, WA

2014-2016

- Developed Ruby on Rails application for HP's Instant Ink Subscription Service
- Increased customer base by over 50x from 30K to over 1M users
- Developed bill payment and point of sale activation systems to support US and overseas customers
- Developed back-end to communicate with over 1M printer embedded systems
- Prototyped new applications using Rails and Sinatra
- Analyzed and improved application performance

Software Development Engineer Siemens - Wilsonville, OR

2012-2014

- Developed new Azure based multi-physics simulator
- Implemented REST APIs using ASP .NET MVC in C#

EDUCATION

Portland State University MS, Computer Science University of Washington BS, Computer Science Pitzer College, BA, Computational Biology